I welcome back post the budget insurance
companies stocks are actually got
hammered on day one but since then
there's a recovery and a lot of my
colleague caught up with Barger Das
Gupta of ICS a long bar to analyze how
the changes in the tax laws would
actually impact general insurance
company so here's an excerpt of that
chat I don't think people are buying
health insurance because of tax break
now they take benefit from the tax break
no doubt but the biggest pool today is
the fact that people need health
insurance and if you look at general
insurance overall in aggregate about 27%
of our business comes from health of
which about 40% of that business is
retail help so roughly about 12% of our
business comes from health now if you
look at the health piece quarter for
sales for the industry is about
one-third is in 33 percent of the volume
gets already higher slightly higher than
25 percent so you can see each person is
maybe because of that also a lot of
renewals happen in that period
traditionally people have bought in the
past so the new business impact
we don't think it'll go it's going to be
made in the material okay the other
issue which we thought would come up in
the budget but didn't come up was came
from the auto industry they are
extremely upset with this high upfront
payment what is your sense you think it
was good it is good to keep it or do you
think responsible people will anyway buy
insurance so you are referring to the
Supreme Court judgment okay so Supreme
Court back in 2018 came up with this
requirement that every five every two
wheeler has to take a five year
insurance and every private car owner
has to take a three years for
third-party liability and that was
largely because the supalen could had
been for a long time pushing the system
to say increase the you know the
adoption of insurance because it's third
party you have to when you drive on the
road you have to have a third party
liability cover that's a law of the land
and this data that we have as an
industry is that roughly 50% of the
vehicles on the road do not have an
insurance and the biggest defaulters are
to either you know to IRA's now I will
give you another data in terms of what
we see on happening
on this adoption of the long term
policies so because Supreme Court every
you know two wheeler guy has to buy a
five-year third-party cover but on old
damage which is the damage to your own
vehicle there's no compulsion you may
not buy an undamaged cover you may buy
one year cover also and you can also buy
five-year cover what we find is almost
20% of our customers are buying
five-year run damage cover so I don't
think insurance is the real reason why
people are you know the many things that
has happened at the same time the cost
of insurance has gone up no doubt but I
think the bigger issue is credit okay
yeah of course credit was a very big
thing but then there is no wriggle room
for the government government decision
there was a Supreme Court decision and
in my view it's actually a correct
decision because the benefit the
customers get is they pay much less for
a cover which you know for example
five-year cover they pay three three and
a half times so they can huge benefit of
way buying a you know five year product
and the other news piece which of course
not related to the budget at all but
motor third party insurance segment is
even the pricing is regulated by the
regulator you think that's the way it
should be or you think it should be
deregulated now so in the long term it
should be digital - no doubt about that
but the challenge today is that if you
see till this motor vehicle Act I think
what they've done good with this act is
that they've taken away one of the real
problems that was there in the bus the
past there was no time limit for
intimation of claims so what we used to
find as an industry was claims would
come after seven eight even twenty years
as an industry had claims which are from
the 80s an accident that supposedly
happened in 1985 you've got a claim you
know they say three four years back
because there's no limit of liability in
in third party liability or there wasn't
till then you motor vehicle and now when
that happens you don't have enough data
as a new company to figure out how long
of the you know how long your claims
will come through because you don't have
data so you need some kind of a
monitoring at a central level to figure
out what is a loss ratio for a for a
third party so it's for that reason the
regulator has continued to tariff it
because individual companies don't have
enough data to price this risk but is
there also I mean
this is something we are picking up from
your own data rising instance of motor
insurance claims actually the incidence
rates what we call incidence is the
frequency of claims to the you know
number of claims do you have it divided
by the number of vehicles that we insure
as they're coming down oh so that's
probably because of the auto industry's
done a better job in terms of safety
standards there is a lot more discipline
on the roads better road being you know
built the the challenge is the cost of
every accident is going up so
effectively the loss ratio is you know
under a bit of pressure but it's not
because of more accidents it's because
each of the accidents are costing us
more now right then and deema that's
talking focus has sources say that a Qi
P will be launched today Mangalam joins
us to fill us in with all those details
Mangalam
absolutely Nigel you know everyone's
been talking about the fact that the
company has been Qi P bound but it
appears as if the Qi P will be launched
today itself is the D mod Q IP that I'm
talking about in which the company will
raise around 4,500 to around five
thousand odd crore rupees the Qi P the
company had taken a Qi P provision for
about two and a half crore shares the
price wasn't known appears that the
price would be very close to where it is
right now itself yesterday's closed was
around twenty one hundred and fifty odd
rupees the price for the Qi P would be
between twenty one hundred and twenty
two hundred itself but perhaps a 5%
discount or so the reason why the
company is raising this money is because
the promoter stake needs to be coming
down from around seventy nine point
seven or percent or eighty odd percent
to down to seventy five percent by March
31st itself this two and a half crore
shell Qi P will reduce the promoter
stake by around three point nine four
percent odd and the rest would perhaps
be done in a couple of weeks from now
when the promoters will offload the
other's shares yrn o FS we had written
to the company a couple of days ago and
the company has still not responded to
our query but you know the final nail as
far as the Qi P is concerned came just a
few minutes ago when the company
reported their results to the exchanges
and out there there was a line which
said that the company's unaudited
condense consolidated in telling
financial statements have been prepared
by the company solely in connection with
a fundraising transaction so that was a
big giveaway and
the fact that the company hasn't
responded over the last couple of
trading sessions we had written to them
on Monday chances are that the Q IP is
likely today itself that's what we
gather from all the investment bankers
all right Mangalam thanks much a quick
break for now lots more in the market
lots of stock specific actions were
lined up
[Music]